<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-05-19T21:43:44-07:00</updated><id>https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Scripted Tea</title><subtitle>Coding tips one brew at a time</subtitle><author><name>Lily</name></author><entry><title type="html">Happy New Year!</title><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/happy-new-year/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy New Year!" /><published>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/happy-new-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/happy-new-year/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/assets/images/posts/image6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! I was on a plane when the clock striked past midnight while coming back on my trip from China. My 2-week vacation went by in a blur, and the next thing I knew I was already back to work. Unfortunately I caught a stomach flu nearing the tail end of my trip so I took a day off to recover. I found that drinking some Chinese medicine really helped with re-gaining my appetite, and after 2 weeks of treatment I was finally able to eat normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most people, I plan on setting some goals for myself this year, but unlike a typical New Years Resolution - goals that you need to stick with for an entire year - it’s much more feasible to set quarterly goals, then review your progress at the end of every quarter. As you already can see, I am currently working on my personal blog/site. What I love about working on this is that not only do I get to code but I also get to make various design choices and get a chance to create my own content. However that also came with its own set of challenges, mostly because it’s my first time going full deep-dive into web development using HTML/CSS/Jekyll/Liquid. I am hoping to finish by the end of the first quarter, but we will see how that goes. I will be writing posts while building the site so there are some content when I launch the site. Can’t wait to see the finished product!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoping to have updates to the site very soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lily</name></author><category term="diary" /><summary type="html">Happy New Year! I was on a plane when the clock striked past midnight while coming back on my trip from China. My 2-week vacation went by in a blur, and the next thing I knew I was already back to work. Unfortunately I caught a stomach flu nearing the tail end of my trip so I took a day off to recover. I found that drinking some Chinese medicine really helped with re-gaining my appetite, and after 2 weeks of treatment I was finally able to eat normally.</summary></entry></feed>