<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.3">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-24T23:33:02-08:00</updated><id>https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Scripted Tea</title><subtitle>Coding and My Matcha Life</subtitle><author><name>Lily</name></author><entry><title type="html">Happy New Year!</title><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/happy-new-year/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Happy New Year!" /><published>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/happy-new-year</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/happy-new-year/">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/assets/images/posts/kyoto1-800by532-43c81d.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; class=&quot;full&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Happy New Year! I was on a plane when the clock striked past midnight while coming back on my trip from China. My 2-week vacation went by in a blur, and the next thing I knew I was already back to work. Unfortunately I caught a stomach flu nearing the tail end of my trip so I took a day off to recover. I found that drinking some Chinese medicine really helped with re-gaining my appetite, and after 2 weeks of treatment I was finally able to eat normally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with most people, I plan on setting some goals for myself this year, but unlike a typical New Years Resolution - goals that you need to stick with for an entire year - it’s much more feasible to set quarterly goals, then review your progress at the end of every quarter. As you already can see, I am currently working on my personal blog/site. What I love about working on this is that not only do I get to code but I also get to make various design choices and get a chance to create my own content. However that also came with its own set of challenges, mostly because it’s my first time going full deep-dive into web development using HTML/CSS/Jekyll/Liquid. I am hoping to finish by the end of the first quarter, but we will see how that goes. I will be writing posts while building the site so there are some content when I launch the site. Can’t wait to see the finished product!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hoping to have updates to the site very soon!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lily</name></author><category term="diary" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Blah</title><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/blah/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Blah" /><published>2019-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2019-01-12T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/blah</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/miscellaneous/blah/">&lt;p&gt;blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahb lahblahblahlblahblahblahb lahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlbl ahblahblahblahblahlbl ahblahblahblahblah lblahblahblahblahblahlblahb lahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblah blahl
blahblahblahbl ahblahlblahblahblahbla hblahlblahblahblahbla hblahlblahblahblahbl ahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl
blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl
blahblahblahblahblahl
blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Lily</name></author><category term="diary" /><category term="fun" /><summary type="html">blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahb lahblahblahlblahblahblahb lahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlbl ahblahblahblahblahlbl ahblahblahblahblah lblahblahblahblahblahlblahb lahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblah blahl blahblahblahbl ahblahlblahblahblahbla hblahlblahblahblahbla hblahlblahblahblahbl ahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl blahblahblahblahblahl blahblahblahblahblahlblahblahblahblahblahl</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Learning Jekyll</title><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/tech/learning-jekyll/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Learning Jekyll" /><published>2016-01-20T13:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-20T13:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/tech/learning-jekyll</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/tech/learning-jekyll/"></content><author><name>Lily</name></author><category term="fun" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Benefits of static site generators</title><link href="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/tech/benefits-of-static-website-generators/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Benefits of static site generators" /><published>2016-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</published><updated>2016-01-19T00:00:00-08:00</updated><id>https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/tech/benefits-of-static-website-generators</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://scriptedtea.github.io/scriptedtea/tech/benefits-of-static-website-generators/">&lt;p&gt;Some of the benefits of a static website generators are that they are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simple&lt;/strong&gt; - makes building and maintaining websites incredibly simple, Static sites are easier to maintian (No databases, no server-side scripts!). User static website generators when you’re after simplicity and want to put the emphasis on the content, which is what you should be doing. It doesn’t really matter, whether you’re focusing on hosting a huge website, or a simple portfolio, static websites can be extremely useful when it comes to saving money, time and resources.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Fast&lt;/strong&gt;: Static files can be served fast. There is no database or templating layer that slows requests down. Additionally, web servers will automatically set caching headers (such as Last-Modified) for static files, which reduce bandwidth usage.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Secure&lt;/strong&gt;, as they do not contain dynamic content, so are immune to the most common attacks. Considering the only thing being served to users’ devices are HTML, CSS and Javascript files&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have versioning&lt;/strong&gt; - Storing content in flat, text files, makes them ideal to be used with version control systems, such as Git.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Utilizing a static site generator means you can build websites with &lt;strong&gt;modern frameworks and workflows&lt;/strong&gt;, with a high degree of productivity and efficiency&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Uses &lt;strong&gt;markdown&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Previewable&lt;/strong&gt;: Because static sites are developed locally, you can play around with the site to your heart’s content without affecting the live site.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name>Lily</name></author><category term="fun" /><summary type="html">We pay a huge price for the underlying complexity of dynamic code running on a server for every request - a price we could avoid paying entirely when this kind of complexity is not needed.</summary></entry></feed>